COURTEZ M. CANNADY

Woodbridge, VA 22192

Phone: 540-287-6266 | Email: courtezcannady@gmail.com LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/courtez-cannady-a8588a108 | GitHub: https://github.com/Tez28 |

Portfolio: https://tez28.github.io/Courtez-Cannady-Portfolio/

SUMMARY

Senior IT/Systems Engineer and U.S. Marine Corps veteran. I have a bachelor's degree in Information Technology Management from Trident University International and a certificate in Full Stack Development from Vanderbilt University. I hold certifications in AWS (Certified Cloud Practitioner, Certified Solutions Architect) and Information Technology Information Library (ITIL) v4. Innovation and design sit at the core of who I am. For the past 14+ years I have strived to help my customers succeed in their missions by successfully designing and maintaining various million-dollar C4ISR systems and web applications ensuring timely delivery and project success. I have played key roles in the strategic design, acquisition and management of IT systems and portfolios inevitably leading to me managing and training diverse groups of engineers and IT professionals. I am excited at the opportunity to advance my career into new technologies and play a role in the evolution of technology.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, jQuery, Bootstrap, Python, + Applications: MongoDB, Express.js, React.js, Node.js, Visual Studios, CLI, GitHub

PROJECTS

Code Jeopardy | github.com/Tez28/code-jeopardy | tez28.github.io/code-jeopardy

- Code Jeopardy is a web application that users can access to take a quiz on Marvel and DC superheroes. It is a short, fun application.
- I am the sole developer of this application. I developed every aspect of the application.
- Tools/Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript

Securelink Passgen | github.com/Tez28/securelink-passgen | tez28.github.io/securelink-passgen/

- Securelink Passgen is a password generating application that users can use to create a randomly generated password. The password can be from 8-128 characters and any value seen on the keyboard.
- I am the sole developer of this application.
- Tools/Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript

Carpe The Day | github.com/Tez28/carpe-the-day | tez28.github.io/carpe-the-day

- Carpe The Day is a web application users can access and use to track their day. The application logs and tracks tasks in past, present and future states.
- I am the sole developer of this application.
- Tools/Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, ¡Query, Moment.js, Bootstrap

EXPERIENCE

Acquisition Software Standards Systems Engineer(contract) Booz Allen Hamilton

2020 - Present Crystal City,VA

Develops and applies advanced software/systems methods, theories, and solutions. Researches and develops solutions to complex and advanced technical problems via the use of agile and other methodologies.

Key Accomplishments:

- Developed RFP Standards Compendium Module. This tool will help the U.S. Army in their development of Request For Proposals and contracting.
- Recognized by the Director of the Office of the Chief Systems Engineer for my role in establishing a Tiger Team (working group) that fosters collaboration between multiple directorates.
- Developed an Integrated Master Schedule outlining the development of a \$20 million Army system spanning a 10-year development timeline.

Sr. Systems Engineer(contract) Mission 1st Group Inc.

2019-2020

Ft. Belvoir, VA

Responsible for overseeing the project lifecycle for Army acquisition programs. Developed request for proposals for the Army to develop Enterprise Information Systems. Designed enterprise information systems for the Army and facilitated the establishment of contracts with offerors and managing the projects to completion.

Key Accomplishments:

- Coordinated and managed teams in the development of RFPs for government projects.
- Provided assessments of infrastructure modernization project costs, design concepts, schedules and plans.
- Evaluated/documented design specifications, installation instructions, and other infrastructure/system related data.
- Developed system architecture that met federal and DoD cyber requirements in accordance with FISMA.

Systems Engineer(contract) STF Ltd.

2018 - 2019 Stafford, VA

Responsible for the design, acquisition and management for SATCOM (satellite communications systems) portfolios supporting the U.S. Marine Corps. Designed/developed Performance Specifications documentations, LOMs (list of materials), Systems Engineering plans and TEMPs (Test and Evaluation Master Plans).

Key Accomplishments:

- Developed key foundational documentation supporting the development of new SATCOM Wideband systems, a \$60 million program.
- Revamped the Independent Verification and Validation testing process for the Satcom team saving schedule time and cost for reviewing, analyzing and testing software and hardware for systems.
- Revamped the Engineering Health Assessment process updating the metrics for determining the health of a portfolio better aligning with industry engineering practices.

Systems Analyst(contract)

2017 - 2018

KForce Washington, DC

Responsible for performing on-site or in-house management, servicing, repair and or installation of VoIP systems. Managed and built VoiP lines through the use of VoIP applications such as Star2Star and Telmetrics. Created and terminated user profiles in the managed VoIP system designing voicemail and mailbox solutions linking to user email. Key Accomplishments:

- Provided technical support to customers on Operation & Maintenance (O&M) aspects of VoIP and legacy Cisco Systems for the Department of Transportations 55,000 employees nationwide.
- Developed a multi-million dollar system for the Department of Transportations VolP network replacing a legacy system that was no longer supported by vendors

Telecom Project Manager AOC Connect

2016 - 2017

Chantilly, VA

Responsible for the Management and oversight of IT Projects. Managed projects IT projects such as OSP and ISP, VoIP and equipment installs.

Key Accomplishments:

- Managed a \$3 million project for the development of a VoIP system to support the National Science Foundations mission as they established a new site in the D.C. area.
- Managed a \$10 million project updating the wireless network infrastructure for the Veterans Affairs Hospital and satellite offices in Ohio.
- Facilitated the collaboration between stakeholders to facilitate the successful completion of more than 10 contracts totaling \$25 million in value.

Systems Engineer(contract) eScience & Technology Solutions, Inc. 2015 - 2016

Stafford, VA

Telecommunications Analyst CACI Inc.

2013 - 2015 Fairfax,

VA

Full Time Student Germanna Community College 2011 - 2013

Tropo-Scatter Communications Operator

Fredericksburg, VA

U.S. Marine Corps

2007 - 2011 Camp Lejeune, NC

EDUCATION

Full Stack Web Development: Vanderbilt University, Nashville, TN

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, ¡Query, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.

Bachelors of Science in Information Technology Management(BTISM): Trident University International, Cypress, CA

OTHER CERTIFICATIONS

Amazon Web Services - Certified Cloud Practitioner 2021 Amazon Web Services(AWS) Certified Solutions Architect Associate 2021 Information Technology Information Library (ITIL) v4 Foundation 2019